CV M2R-RO Internship

BELDJILALI Abdelkader

Motivation and Objective

In the context of the Operations Research Master of Toulouse (M2R-RO), I would like to carry out a 6-month Internship in optimization field beginning in the first term of 2018. My main motivation is to tackle an optimization problem to try and help the host structure, learn more about OR and/or AI and complete the three-year training at the Civil Aviation School, namely the ENAC, http://m2rit-ro.recherche.enac.fr/debouches/proposer-un-stage.

Education and Trainings

- Double diploma Engineer ENAC and Master OR Third year ENAC : System Engineering, Air Transport Optimization and Master's degree in Operations Research (M2 OR) : Optimisation combinatoire avancée, Méthodes stochastiques pour l'optimisation globale, Graphes et réseaux, Optimisation globale déterministe, Applications de l'optimisation au transport aérien, Thèmes contemporains en optimisation, Toulouse University Paul Sabatier (UPS). This M2 OR is co-accredited by the Toulouse Engineering Schools : ENAC, ENSEEIHT, ENSIACET and ISAE Supaero, Toulouse, France, https://m2rit-ro.recherche.enac.fr/files/7215/0419/4058/nouveauM2RO.pdf.
- 2015-2018 National Civil Aviation Engineering School: ENAC, Major: SITA i.e. Computer Systems for Air Transport, formely known as System option(S), Minor 1: Economics, Minor 2: Information Systems Security (ISS), other: Stochastic processes, Combinatorial and Continuous Optimization, Toulouse, France, http://www.enac.fr/.
- Various Trainings in Sopra HR Access 9, Electronics and various Windows and AIX Unix Softwares used by Air Traffic Control, UNIX, Red Hat Admin, Network, IT Security, C++, Design Patterns, JAVA, UML, SOA Architectures, XML, HTML, Web Services, PHP MySQL, SPIP, Georeferencing, Geographic Information Systems (GIS).
- 2003-2004 Master 2 of Science(MSc), predoctoral research, in Atmosphere, Ocean and Continental Surface (OASC), Paul Sabatier University (UPS), Toulouse, http://www.enm.meteo.fr/content/master-oasc.
- 1998-2001 **Engineer in meteorology**, *National Meteorology Engineering School (ENM)*, Toulouse, France, http://www.enm.meteo.fr/.
- 1996-1997 Master of Science, postgraduate specialization, in Physics of Electronics and Optoelectronics Components, *Nantes University*, France.
- 1992-1993 Master of Science, predoctoral research, in Molecular Physical Chemistry, Engineering School of Centrale Paris (ECP) and University of Paris Sud (Paris 11), France.

- 1990-1991 Agrégation de physique, option physique, postgraduate specialization, http://agregation-physique.org.
- 1987-1990 **Master's degree in physics**, *Lille University (USTL)*, France, Master's Thesis on Neutron Scattering http://master-physique.univ-lille1.fr/.

Work experience

- 2014-2015 HR Access Software support Engineer at the Human Ressources Direction, *Meteo-France*, Paris.
- 2012-2014 **Aviation Safety Systems Electronics Engineer**, *French Civil Aviation*, Paris. Specialized Maintenance Engineer: Maintenance and upgrade of radio, pabx, telecom, energy and network systems, radar visualization and flight plans processing used by Air Trafic Control (ATC)
- 1998-2012 Meteorologist, Meteo-France, Toulouse.

 2008-2012 -> ECMWF's softwares: Metview, Magics user support, reverse conception and code modifications of Object Oriented C++ Magics library. http://www.ecmwf.int/, 2004-2008 -> Head of Oise Meteo-France Departmental Center of Meteorology, Meteoroligical Research: Research on Rossby Wave Breaking (RWB) and their interactions with tropical cyclones, MOTHY/MERCATOR models coupling, ...
 - 1997 Internship in Electronics, *DPV Electronics Compagny*, Jeumont France. PIC 16F84 microcontroller programming and Quality Assurance ISO 9000:1994
- 1993-1996 **Professor of Physics**, North of France.
- 1990-1992 **Cooperation in Central Africa**, French Ministry of Defence and Ministry of Cooperation, Equivalent to Peace Corps for US citizens.

Skills

Computer Science

- Unix/Linux Unix to Linux port of any Software.
 - OOP Reverse Design and modifications of C++ Softwares.
- Languages C/C++/IDE code::block, Python/IDE PyCharm, Git/Github, Languages Eclipse et IntelliJ, Bash, Fortran.
 - OS UNIX AIX, RHEL, CentOS, Fedora, Scientific Linux(SL), OpenSUSE, Debian, Ubuntu. Languages
 - French mother tongue
 - English **B2 level**

Extra-curricular activities

Interests Music, Movies, Fedora Open Source GNU/Linux software.

Private Pilot Theoretical PPL and 17 hours of flight on DA40 http://www.diamondaircraft.com/aircraft/da40-ng/